Alison Barber

Phone: 816-308-1182 | Email: arbarber.ab@gmail.com
LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/alison-barber-b6b45444/

GitHub: https://github.com/ARBarber0510 | Portfolio: https://arbarber0510.github.io/portfolio/

Summary

Junior Web Developer focused on creating effective client-based software that is both elegant and easy to navigate. Known for creativity, analytical skills, and quick adaptability. Skills include CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, and responsive web design. Ten years' experience in hotel and hospitality industry, most recently in client event operations.

Technical Skills

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, APIs, Bootstrap, jQuery, PureCSS, SASS, Leaflet.js, Moment.js, Popper.js, jQuery, Responsive Design, MySQL, MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, GitHub, Heroku, Material UI, User Authentication

Projects

Simple State

An interactive application with clickable map and display to generate trending news based on specific US territories.

Languages/Tools Used: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React, Material UI, LeafletJS

GitHub: https://github.com/JPBrickhouse/projectthree
 Deployed Project: https://project-three-2020.herokuapp.com/

Picniq

A dynamic application which provides user with closest restaurants and parks to help plan a socially distanced outing.

• Languages/Tools Used: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap, PureCSS, Popper.js

GitHub: https://github.com/JPBrickhouse/Picniq
 Deployed Project: https://jipbrickhouse.github.io/Picniq/

README Generator

A command line application that generates concise README through a series of questions.

Languages/Tools: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Node.js

GitHub: https://github.com/ARBarber0510/README-Generator
 Deployed Project: https://arbarber0510.github.io/README-Generator/

Experience

Hyatt Regency Chicago

Chicago, IL 2018 – 2020

Group Reservations Coordinator

Hired as a liaison between client meeting planners and hotel rooms division. Responsible for building and managing group reservations blocks & websites, setting up billing, and ensuring all requests made by guests deemed Very Important Persons (VIPs) are met.

Key Accomplishments:

- Received employee of the month award in October 2018 for exemplary work managing the group website, billing, and communication of a large-scale event with up to 5,000 attendees.
- Took on additional supervisory roles to guarantee the success of the operations department during the hotel workers union strike in September 2018.
- Collaborated with National Basketball Association (NBA) to ensure the safety and success of the NBA All Star weekend in February 2020.

Hyatt Lodge on McDonald's Campus

Oak Brook, IL 2017 - 2018

Reservations Coordinator

Hired to build and manage group blocks, volume account rates, and contracted discounted rates for Hyatt's many business partners. In addition to reservation management, maintained strong relationships with the hotel's owners, clients, and third-party event planners and vendors.

Key Accomplishments:

- Earned employee of the month award, Stars of the Lodge, in May 2018 for successfully managing all group blocks in Quarter One of 2018.
- Collaborated with the Events and Front Desk staff to ensure the successful arrival and departures and all McDonald's University attendees.
- Developed and maintained strong relationship with main clients, McDonald's throughout the transition process to their new headquarters in downtown Chicago.

Hyatt Regency St. Louis at the Arch

St. Louis, MO 2014 – 2017

First hired as a Food & Beverage intern in May 2014. Was quickly promoted to a Front Desk Agent in August 2014, and then to Group Sales Coordinator in July 2015. In January 2017, moved into the role of Event Concierge.

Key Accomplishments:

- Collaborated with hotel's leadership committee and clients to successfully execute a large-scale VIP event during the full renovation of sleeping rooms.
- Successfully managed the VIP rooms blocks to ensure the success of St. Louis Cardinals' Winter Warm Up fundraisers in 2016 & 2017.
- Named a Gateway Service Team Member, the hotel's employee of the quarter award, in September 2016.

Education

Northwestern University, Evanston, IL

Certificate, Full Stack Web Development

2020

University of Missouri, Columbia, MO

Bachelor of Science, Hospitality Management, Event and Meeting Planning

2014